JOSE CARLOS ROMÁN RUBIO

Software engineer

Website: https://josecarlosroman.com

Latest CV can be downloaded at: https://github.com/jcdotnet/curriculum

BACKGROUND

2014

Ingeniería técnica en Informática de Sistemas (3-year university degree focused on Computer Engineering, Information Technology and Software Engineering). Final grade: NOTABLE. FYP defended on 13th of March and marked as SOBRESALIENTE. University of Málaga.

SKILLS

Computer science

Total experience in years (Experience in years on projects to individuals, institutions and companies)

< Less than a year of experience > More than 10 years of experience

Software development		Microsoft		Java	
Computer programming	> (7)	C# (updated to ver6)	6 (5)	Java (updated to Java 9)	4 (0)
C/C++	1 (0)	TypeScript	2 (0)	Data Access / JDBC	1 (0)
Python	< (0)	Desktop (Windows Forms)	4 (3)	Java GUI	1 (0)
Objective C	< (0)	Desktop (WPF)	3 (2)	Java EE	1 (<)
Swift	< (0)	ASP.NET	2 (1)	Spring (updated to ver5)	< (0)
Git	3 (<)	ASP.NET MVC	1 (0)	Apache Tomcat	1 (1)
Subversion	1 (1)	SOAP Web services (asmx)	4 (3)	Hibernate	< (0)
		SOAP Web services (WCF)	1(1)	Apache Maven	< (0)
		REST Web services (Web API)	1 (0)		
		SSRS, SSAS	1 (<)		
		Entity Framework ORM	< (0)		

Web		JavaScript		PHP	
HTTP (requests, messages,)	> (4)	JavaScript (updated to ES6)	> (5)	PHP	> (4)
REST API	4 (1)	jQuery	> (5)	Composer	1 (0)
HTML (updated to ver5)	> (4)	rxJS	1 (0)	Laravel (updated to ver5)	2 (0)
CSS (updated to ver3)	> (5)	Node.js, NPM	3 (<)	Symfony (updated to ver3)	< (0)
SASS	2 (0)	Express	1 (0)	WordPress	3 (3)
Bootstrap (updated to ver4b)	3 (1)	Angular (upadted to ver5)	2 (0)	WooCommerce	2 (1)
Foundation	< (0)	React (updated to ver16)	1 (<)	Prestashop	1 (<)
SEO tecniques	1 (1)	Vue	< (0)	Joomla!	< (<)
Apache HTTP server	4 (3)	Ionic Framework	1 (0)	Drupal	< (0)
Firebase	1 (0)	NativeScript	< (0)	Doctrine ORM < (0)	
		Mongoose ODM	1 (0)	Eloquent ORM 1 (0)	
		Tools (grunt, gulp, webpack)	2 (<)		

Mobile App development		Databases		Other	
Android development	2 (<)	SQL	> (6)	Computer architecture	2 (<)
iOS development	< (0)	Relational databases	> (6)	Operating systems	> (1)
Apache Cordova	1 (0)	MySQL	7 (5)	Linux	1 (<)
Material Design	1 (0)	MongoDB	1 (0)	Computer Networks	> (0)

Languages

Upper-intermediate in written English.

Personal skills

- Organized, critical thinking, good at solving problems, efficient, self-motivated

		_	
	OJ		

2016/01 – 2016/09	Healthcare desktop application. Skills: .NET, WPF, MySQL, Business Intelligence
2012/10 - 2015/03	Sports training software. Skills: .NET, winForms, web services, SQL Server.

EXPERIENCE

2016/01 – present	Software engineer. Self-employed
2014/09 – 2014/11	Programmer at Grupo JyA.
2014/06 – 2014/09	.NET and PHP Programmer at BOLT accelerator.
2008/06 - 2010/01	Owner and manager of a fashion and accessories shop.

COURSES AND CERTIFICATES

2017	Full Stack Web and Multiplatform Mobile App Development. The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology. <u>Verified certificate and courses.</u>
2017	Server-side Development with NodeJS, Express and MongoDB. Verified certificate and grade.
2017	Ionic and Cordova. Verified certificate and grade.
2017	Front-End JavaScript Frameworks: Angular. Verified certificate and grade.
2017	UDEMY: https://www.udemy.com/user/josecarlosromanrubio/
2016	Front-End JavaScript Frameworks: AngularJS. Verified certificate and grade.
2016	MongoDB using the MEAN stack. MongoDB. Self-paced. Grade achieved: 100%.
2015	Web Application Development with JavaScript and MongoDB. University of London. Length: 4 weeks. Grade achieved: 100%
2015	Intro to meteor.js development. University of London. Duración: 4 semanas. Calificación: 92%.
2015	Interactive programming in Python. Rice university. Length: 8 weeks. Grade achieved: 100%
2015	HTML5.2x: Advanced techniques. W3C. Length: 4 weeks. Grade achieved: 86%
2015	Game programming with C#. UCCS. Length: 12 weeks. Grade achieved: 100%
2015	CS188.1x: Artificial Intelligence. UC Berkeley. Length: 12 weeks. Grade achieved: 84%.
2015	Programming Mobile Applications for Android Handheld Systems. University of Maryland. Length: 8 weeks. Grade achieved: 94.8%.
2012	English B1 certificate. EOI Málaga
2007	Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist (.NET framework 2.0). Forman. Length: 670 hours.
2006	Desarrollo de aplicaciones J2EE with work experience in Novasoft. Forman. Length: 360 hours. Course outline. Certificate of completion